MOHIT MISHRA

+91 (702) 321-5632 | *Gmail*- mohitmishra786687@gmail.com | *LinkedIn* - https://bit.ly/3jK5YVW | *Github*- https://bit.ly/3bxctGu | *Medium*- https://bit.ly/3CC8epi | Jaipur, Rajasthan

SUMMARY

Machine learning developer with a great passion for storytelling. I believe that word and data are the two most powerful tools which can change the whole world. I am very strong in teamwork and I believe that in order to achieve difficult projects and tasks, we must work with other people and bring in their skills and experiences. I am also very good at working under pressure and I actually prefer to be under the situation where pressure is on because I believe that is where I am at my best.

EDUCATION

Lovely Professional University

Jalandhar, Punjab

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering

EXPECTED 08/2023

Major in Computer Science(CS); Minors in Machine Learning

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

[Omdena]

Palo Alto, California, United States

09/2021 - Present

[Job Role:- Junior ML Engineer]

- Led the team of 4 people in creating the ML prediction model for resource allocation purposes to predict and help those at risk of eviction/homeless in Texas (like Chronic Homeless AI mode(CHAI)).
- Improved accuracy of the model from 82% to 91% in the career recommendation model.
- Proposed a solution for homelessness in Texas. Motivated more than 3 people to continue their journey in Machine Learning.
- Assisted a team of 7 people in using edge computing and cloud development for model deployment and management.

[iNeuron.ai]

Bengaluru, Karnataka

[Job Role:- Machine Learning Intern]

07/2021 - 09/2021

- Developed a solution that should be able to predict whether the mushroom is poisonous or edible.
- Used a random forest algorithm for getting the solution for the drug activity problem.
- Created a web app for the visualization of drug activity using streamlit.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

[Tea Leaf Detector]

06/2021-07/2021

- Developed a detector and classifier model which will detect the correct image and classify its quality.
- Developed Flask API and used it for the deployment into Microsoft Azure.

[Chatbot]

06/2021-07/2021

- Used the T5 model and the Reformer, also known as the efficient Transformer, to generate a dialogue between two bots.
- Developed a model that will take input as a conversation and not only will it answer that conversation, but the chatbot will also ask a question back.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: Pandas, Data Modeling, Predictive Modeling, Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch, Scikit Learn, Unit
 Testing and CI/CD, Python, Strong Programming Skills, Data Structures, Classification, Regression, AWS, Azure,
 Data Mining, PySpark ML.
- Soft Skills: Time Management,, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Teamwork and Collaboration
- Languages: Fluent in English, Hindi
- Online Courses and Certificates: Certified [Google Analytics], Machine Learning Certificate [Stanford]
- Volunteering: Volunteering Google Developer Student Club, Google Crowdsource

HONORS AND AWARDS

- Of Genomes And Genetics: HackerEarth Machine Learning Challenge:- Hackathon Rank 46 out of 2400
- 4 Star coder at Codechef (Rating of 1818)